Parshan Pakiman

♠ parshanpakiman.github.io/homepage

in linkedin.com/in/parshan-pakiman

github.com/parshanpakiman

ppakim2@uic.edu

(*) +1 312 493 1304

C December 2020

OVERVIEW

I am a Ph.D. candidate in Information and Decision Sciences at the University of Illinois at Chicago. My research focuses on developing self-adapting algorithms to simplify the implementation and hand-engineering needed to solve sequential decision-making problems. My research advances machine learning, approximate dynamic programming, reinforcement learning (RL), inverse RL, online learning, and high-dimensional sampling. I employ state-of-the-art platforms such as TensorFlow, Gurobi, Nevergrad, and OpenAI Gym for large-scale computing.

EDUCATION

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC), Chicago, IL

Ph.D. in: Information and Decision Sciences

Areas of research: Machine Learning and Operations Management Co-advisors: Professors Selva Nadarajah and Negar Soheili

University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC), Chicago, IL

M.Sc. in: Business Analytics

University of Tehran (UT), Tehran, Iran

B.Sc. in: Applied Mathematics

(Expected) Fall 2021

Spring 2017 -(Expected) Fall 2021

Spring 2017 -

Fall 2012 - Fall 2016

EXPERIENCES

• Working with a major technology provider in fast-fashion sector to adaptively learn changing customer demand and modify pricing strategies to maximize revenue (a related research paper is available upon request).

Spring 2019 -Present

• Working with a major e-commerce company to optimize the dimension of cardboard boxes to reduce packaging waste and to ensure high worker throughput (a related research paper is in progress).

Spring 2019 -Present

• Collaborated with Foresight ROI, Inc on a marketing lift forecasting and campaign optimization project (link to the resulting research paper: https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3292500.3330788).

Fall 2017 - Summer 2019

• Teaching and implementation experience in graduate classes with data mining, statistical learning, machine learning, and operations management.

Fall 2014 - Present

• Collaborator on a multi-university and industry initiative to develop an open-source approximate dynamic programming and reinforcement learning platform to solve business problems.

Fall 2019

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Solving large-scale sequential decision making problems by combining techniques from approximate dynamic programming, randomized and high-dimensional sampling, and optimization.
- Developing data-driven algorithms that leverage forecasts to compute robust decisions in application domains such as pricing, retailing, e-commerce, and marketing.
- Deriving business insights and prescribing optimized decisions by developing new machine learning and reinforcement learning methods.

Published or Submitted Papers

• Self-adapting Robustness in Demand Learning. Coauthors: Boxiao Chen, Selvaprabu Nadarajah and Stefanus Jasin. Submitted to Operations Research. http://arxiv.org/abs/2011.10690.

Fall 2020

• Self-guided Approximate Linear Programs. Coauthors: Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Negar Soheili, and Qihang Lin. Major revision at Management Science. https://arxiv.org/abs/2001.02798.

Spring 2020 Summer 2019

• SMOILE: A Shopper Marketing Optimization and Inverse Learning Engine. Coauthors: Abhilash Reddy Chenreddy, Selvaprabu Nadarajah, Ranganathan Chandrasekaran, and Rick Abens. In Proceedings of the 25th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD '19). https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3292500.3330788. Acceptance rate for oral presentation is 6.4%.

WORKING RESEARCH PAPERS

• Managing Packing Efficiency and Sustainability in E-commerce: A Semi-supervised Learning Approach. Coauthors: Present Selvaprabu Nadarajah and Yun Fong Lim. Work in progress.

• Convex Optimization using Random Features. Coauthors: Selva Nadarajah and Negar Soheili. Work in progress.

resen

Awards and Honor	s	
Doctoral scholarship and fellowship:	Department of Information and Decision Sciences, University of Illinois at Chicago	Since Spring 2017
Top student award:	Department of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer Science, University of Tehran	Fall 2016
Technical qualification:	RoboCup Iran open, soccer 2D simulation league	Fall 2016
Technical qualification:	Khwarizmi international award, soccer 2D simulation league	Fall 2010
TECHNICAL SKILLS		
Programming language: Python package: Software: Operating systems:	Python, C++, C, R, Java, HTML, JavaScript NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciKitLearn, PyTorch, GurobiPy, Nevergrad, Pyomo Matlab, Tableau, Microsoft/Libre Office, RapidMiner Linux, MacOS, Windows	
Invited Talks And	Poster Presentations	
Self-adapting Robustne		
	RMS Annual Meeting, Virtual	Fall 2020
Talk: INFO	RMS Revenue Management and Pricing, https://youtu.be/DrioI3lLiUc, Virtual	Fall 2020
Self-guided Approxima		
	PS 2020, Workshop on Self-Supervised Learning: Theory and Practice.	Fall 2020
	S 30th Annual Conference, Washington D.C.	Spring 2019
	RMS Annual Meeting, Phoenix, AZ	Fall 2018
Talk: POMS	S 29th Annual Conference, Houston, TX	Spring 2018
Talk & Poster: ACM	rketing Optimization and Inverse Learning Engine SIGKDD, International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining //youtu.be/eWoBr3JDisc, Anchorage, AK	Summer 2019
	iency and Sustainability in E-commerce: A Semi-supervised Learning Approach osium on Energy, Environment $\mathring{\sigma}$ Sustainability (SEES), Virtual	Spring 2020
Service		
Reviewer		
Annals of Operations Research Computers & Operations Research Electronic Commerce Research Information Systems and Operational Research		Since Fall 2020 Since Spring 2019 Since Spring 2018 Since Fall 2018
TEACHING EXPERIEN	CES	
Lecturer for statistical models and methods for business analytics		Spring 2019 - Fall

Topic: Applications of regression, classification and likelihood maximization

Slides: https://chicagodatascience.github.io/s19/575/

Teaching Assistant, University of Illinois at Chicago

Advanced text analytics for Business (IDS 566)

Business data mining (IDS 472) Business forecasting (IDS 476) Data science for online customer analytics (IDS 594)

Introduction to operations management (IDS 532) Statistical models and methods for business analytics (IDS 575)

Teaching Assistant, University of Tehran

Introduction to numerical analysis and scientific computing

Numerical linear algebra

Since Spring 2017

2019

Spring 2014 - 2016